Empire State Federation of Women's Clubs; Records apap041
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Subject Files of Financial Secretary, 1948-1981; 4; 1.0 cubic ft.
  - NACWC Per Capita Tax Reports, 1965 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files of Financial Secretary), Folder 29)
  - NACWC Per Capita Tax Reports, 1966 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files of Financial Secretary), Folder 30)
  - NACWC Per Capita Tax Reports, 1967 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files of Financial Secretary), Folder 31)
  - NACWC Per Capita Tax Reports, 1968 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files of Financial Secretary), Folder 32)
  - NACWC Per Capita Tax Reports, 1969 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files of Financial Secretary), Folder 33)
  - NACWC Per Capita Tax Reports, 1970 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files of Financial Secretary), Folder 34)
  - NACWC Per Capita Tax Reports, 1971 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files of Financial Secretary), Folder 35)
  - NACWC Per Capita Tax Reports, 1972 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files of Financial Secretary), Folder 36)
  - Negro Braille Magazine Contributions, ca. 1969 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files of Financial Secretary), Folder 37)
  - Reports of Auditor, 1966-1971 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files of Financial Secretary), Folder 38)
  - Reports of Ways and Means Commitee, 1970-1971 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files of Financial Secretary), Folder 39)
  - Victoria Earle Matthews Scholarship Fund Contributions, 1969-1972 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files of Financial Secretary), Folder 40)
- Subject Files of Treasurer, 1938-1977; 5; 0.20 cubic ft.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  This series consists of materials generated or maintained by the ESFWC treasurer. Materials include correspondence (1960), financial reports (1964-1968, 1970-1972, 1977), ledgers (1958-1961, 1967-1968) detailing receipts and disbursements, miscellaneous receipts (1966, 1969-1973) that were not listed or not itemized in financial reports drafted by the treasurer or the financial secretary, a photocopy of the passbook of the Newburgh Savings Bank savings account used to fund the ESFWC's special projects (1938-1964) and documents relating to the account, and a report from the ESFWC Raffle Committee (1969). Also included in this series are the expense reports (1966-1976) turned in by other ESFWC. NB: although the treasurer was customarily responsible for reimbursing officers, the ledgers and reports created by the financial secretary reveal that the financial secretary occasionally performed this task.
  - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files of Treasurer), Folder 1)
  - Expense Reports of Officers and Committees, 1966-1981 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files of Treasurer), Folder 2)
  - Financial Reports, 1964-1977 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files of Treasurer), Folder 3)
  - Ledger, 1958-1961 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files of Treasurer), Folder 4)
  - Ledger, 1967-1968 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files of Treasurer), Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Receipts, 1966-1973 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files of Treasurer), Folder 6)
  - Newburgh Project Fund Account Passbook and Trust Account Card, 1938-1964 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files of Treasurer), Folder 7)
  - Raffle Committee Report, 1969 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files of Treasurer), Folder 8)
- ESFWC Subject Files, 1952-1991; 6; 0.40 cubic ft.
  This series contains materials detailing the organizational structure and functions of the ESFWC. Records include photocopies of the ESFWC's 1927 certificate of incorporation and the 1987 documents amending its incorporation, annual reports of the president (1974-1975, 1977), the ESFWC constitution and bylaws (c. 1966, 1968, 1978), membership cards (c.1970, 1981), membership directories and club rosters (1963, circa1965, 1966, 1970, 1973-1977, 1983), newsletters (c.1955, 1960, 1965, circa1971, 1974-1976, 1978-80), reports of the Constitution Revision Committee (1976, circa1987), and state programs of action (1980, circa1982). Other materials include the ESFWC song (1971?), a prayer litany (undated), records documenting annual observances of Harriet Tubman Day (1974-1975), and a partial organizational history (1952). Also included are materials documenting the activities of a constituent club, the F. Willia Davis Woman's Club of New Rochelle (1979), and biographical information about several club members (1971, 1973, 1978-1981, 1987).
  - 1927 Certificate of Incorporation and 1987 Certificate of Amendment (Box 1 (6-ESFWC Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Annual Reports of President, 1974-1977 (Box 1 (6-ESFWC Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Awards Luncheon and Dinner Programs, 1970-1990 (Box 1 (6-ESFWC Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Biographical Information About Members, 1971-1987 (Box 1 (6-ESFWC Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Constitution and Bylaws, ca. 1966-1978 (Box 1 (6-ESFWC Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Correspondence of Journal Chairman, 1960 (Box 1 (6-ESFWC Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Electoral Procedure, Undated (Box 1 (6-ESFWC Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - "Family"/"The International Year of the Family", Undated (Box 1 (6-ESFWC Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - F. Willia Davis Woman's Club, Inc., 1967-1979 (Box 1 (6-ESFWC Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Harriet Tubman Day, 1974-1975 (Box 1 (6-ESFWC Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - History of Empire State Federation of Women's Clubs, 1952 (Box 1 (6-ESFWC Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - M.C. Lawton Club Fiftieth Anniversary Photograph, 1969 (Box 1 (6-ESFWC Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Member Addresses, 1964-ca. 1979 (Box 1 (6-ESFWC Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Membership Application Forms, Undated (Box 1 (6-ESFWC Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Membership Cards, ca. 1970-1981 (Box 1 (6-ESFWC Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Membership Directories, Club Rosters, and Lists of Officers, 1963-1983 (Box 1 (6-ESFWC Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Newsletters, ca. 1955-1980 (Box 1 (6-ESFWC Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Prayer Litany, Undated (Box 1 (6-ESFWC Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Press Releases, 1980 (Box 1 (6-ESFWC Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Reports of Constitution Revision Commitee, 1976 (Box 1 (6-ESFWC Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Reports to Northeastern Federation of Women's Clubs, 1975-1981 (Box 1 (6-ESFWC Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - State Programs, 1980-1982 (Box 1 (6-ESFWC Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Stay at Home Tea, 1966 (Box 1 (6-ESFWC Subject Files), Folder 24)
- General Subject Files, 1952-1990; 7; 0.40 cubic ft.
  This series contains materials generated by the Northeastern Federation of Women and the National Association of Colored Women's Clubs and collected by the ESFWC. Records created by the NFWC include executive board and annual convention minutes (1967, 1981, 1989), programs and other convention materials (1975, 1979, 1981, 1987), and newsletters (1958, 1972, 1974, 1977-1978). Records documenting the activities of the NACWC include a copy of the constitution (undated), convention minutes (1968, 1978, 1980, 1982), programs and other convention materials (1952, 1970, 1976, 1978, 1980, 1988, 1990), periodicals (1972, 1976-1979), and reports of the president (1987). A handful of documents in this series concern the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (1980 ?) and the National Urban League (1974, 1979), both of which received funds from the ESFWC. Other materials document social issues and other organizations in which the ESFWC took an interest, among them the Front Royal Educational Fund Committee (c.1959), the New Rochelle Club of the National Association of Negro Business and Professional Women's Clubs (1975), and the Westchester County Section of the National Council of Negro Women (1990).
  - Black Entertainment Television, "AIDS in the Black Community", 1987 (Box 1 (7-General Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Front Royal Educational Fund Committee, ca. 1959 (Box 1 (7-General Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Massachusetts State Union of Women's Clubs, 1959 (Box 1 (7-General Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, ca. 1980 (Box 1 (7-General Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - National Association of Colored Women's Clubs Constitution, Undated (Box 1 (7-General Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - National Association of Colored Women's Clubs Annual Convention Materials, 1952-1990 (Box 1 (7-General Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - National Association of Colored Women's Clubs Annual Convention Minutes, 1968-1982 (Box 1 (7-General Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - National Association of Colored Women's Clubs Periodicals, 1972-1979 (Box 1 (7-General Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - National Association of Colored Women's Clubs President's Report, 1987 (Box 1 (7-General Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - National Association of Colored Women's Clubs/United Negro College Fund, 1981 (Box 1 (7-General Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - National Association of Colored Women's Clubs, "Traditionally Black Public Colleges...", 1978 (Box 1 (7-General Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - National Urban League, 1974-1979 (Box 1 (7-General Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - New Jersey State Federation of Women's Clubs, 1990 (Box 1 (7-General Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - New Rochelle Club, National Association of Negro Business and Professional Women's Clubs, Inc., 1975 (Box 1 (7-General Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - New Rochelle Community Action Agency, "It's Your Community", 1966 (Box 1 (7-General Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Northeastern Federation of Women's Clubs Annual Convention Materials, 1975-1987 (Box 1 (7-General Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Northeastern Federation of Women's Clubs Executive Board and Annual Convention Meeting Minutes, 1967-1989 (Box 1 (7-General Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Northeastern Federation of Women's Clubs Lists of Officers, ca. 1971-ca. 1978 (Box 1 (7-General Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Northeastern Federation of Women's Clubs Newsletters, 1958-1978 (Box 1 (7-General Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Westchester County Section, National Council of Negro Women, Inc., 1990 (Box 1 (7-General Subject Files), Folder 20)